<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rstudio on Graph My Undergrad</title>
    <link>/tags/rstudio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rstudio on Graph My Undergrad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/rstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring my Google Fit Data</title>
      <link>/2020/07/01/exploring-my-google-fit-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/01/exploring-my-google-fit-data/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A lot has changed as a result of the Covid-19 pandemic, including the fact that we basically don&amp;rsquo;t leave our houses to see our friends, everything happens on Zoom, and we&amp;rsquo;re moving around a lot less (my summer internship has me examining large-scale mobility data changes, more on that later).
However, one of my pre-pandemic goals was to get better at working out every day and keeping in shape. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to take a look at the Google fit data (collected from my smartphone, auto-tracking steps, moving/active minutes) before and after the pandemic to see what it looks like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightning Talks with the Tidyverse Team</title>
      <link>/2019/10/29/lightning-talks-with-the-tidyverse-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/10/29/lightning-talks-with-the-tidyverse-team/</guid>
      <description>After some magic where I was suddenly moved up 6 spots on a wait list of 25 people, I was recently able to attend the Lightning Talks by the Tidyverse Team, hosted by R Ladies Boston and the Greater Boston UseR meetup groups! I&amp;rsquo;ve been going to R meetups since last Spring, but I really enjoy meeting new people and I was inordinately excited at the potential of meeting everyone&amp;rsquo;s favourite RStudio scientist, Hadley Wickham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach, WiSTEM, and R</title>
      <link>/2019/05/08/r-outreach/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2019/05/08/r-outreach/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I’m going to talk a little bit less about graphs and data, and more about outreach.
As a minority in STEM, I’m really interested in outreach, science commmunication, and the increase of diversity in my field. So when the STEM Ambassadors Program at UMass offered the opportunity to create an activity centered around my research interests to “pitch” my science to a group of middle schoolers, I jumped at the chance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>